After all of my matches were finally over, I got horribly sick with a fever.
I spent December 31st alone in my dimly lit room.
I don't know if I've ever been that sick before.
Thirsty. So thirsty. Water.
I have to... I have to eat something.
I gotta take more medicine.
But there's only one pill left.
I need to buy more. But how? I can't... do anything.
I'll forget it. I'll just... go back to sleep. A deep sleep.
Maybe when I wake up, my fever will be gone. As if it was all a bad dream.
I stayed in the apartment alone for days.
I was burning up with a fever.
Having the same dream over and over again.
It's been that way ever since I was a kid.
The same dream haunting me again and again.
I find myself going up a never-ending escalator.
It's not like it's really scary or anything.
I just keep going up.
Higher and higher.
And when I finally reach the top...
There's no way to get back down.
Who is it?
Who's there?
It's too loud.
Stop it. Knock it off.
I can't get up.
Ray! Ray!
Momo's here. Why?
Why?
As I expected. I knew you had a cold.
All right, guys. Go!
Roger!
Yay!
It's Ray!
Hina, secure the pillow.
Roger!
Ray, grab your phone, wallet, and keys.
Stay in your PJs and put on a jacket.
Let's wrap this scarf around your neck.
There's a taxi waiting outside.
Ah, a taxi.
But why?
Where are we going?
What do you mean where?
We're taking you to the doctor right now.
If you have the flu, you'll be quarantined and we'll take care of you here.
But if it's just a cold...
We're taking you to our house.
Here you go.
Thank goodness it wasn't the flu.
We have to be very careful not to let Grandpa or Momo get exposed.
The egg porridge is ready.
Try and have some.
I saw your kitchen, Ray, and you haven't been eating much.
Do you like pickled plums?
Here, have one.
It can help to make you feel better, especially when you have a fever.
Hold still a sec.
Lift up your chin.
Good.
Keep this towel around your neck.
I'll change it if it gets sweaty.
The porridge will heat you up a lot.
Sweating it out will help reduce your fever.
We've got plenty of towels, so no problem there.
Sorry.
I just need to wipe off your forehead a bit.
Momo, now!
I'll bet you now!
Um, thank you for the meal.
That's yummy!
Momo wants a two!
No, Momo, this is only for Ray.
All right, you ate quite a bit.
That's great.
Why don't you have some tea and go lie down?
But before that, don't you think we should call your family?
They must be worried about you.
Yeah, but I live on my own now, so we don't have to call.
Tenderines!
Kitties don't like citrus!
Yummy tenderines!
Hmm.
On your own, huh?
Let me see your phone for a minute.
Hasn't your battery been dead for a few days?
You can't say you're alone with all these messages.
People are worried about you.
You see?
Yeah.
Hello?
Um, hi, Father.
It's Ray.
Ray, is that you?
Are you all right?
What's wrong?
Do you have a cold?
You weren't answering your phone, so I was gonna stop by your place.
Are you sure you're okay?
The moment I heard my father's voice on the phone,
I realized just how selfish I'd been.
From his voice, I could tell that he was really worried about me.
What an idiot.
All this time, I had only been thinking about myself.
But, I hadn't even thought about those around me.
Ray?
How are you doing?
Feel like getting up?
You should have some food and medicine.
I just knew it.
Can you wake me up right before midnight?
Let me know when New Year's breakfast is ready.
Try not to wake me up until it's time to eat.
I just knew this would happen, as usual.
It used to be even worse.
We had three more people back then and it was pretty cramped.
There wasn't even enough room to breathe.
Three people.
Oh, I see.
Their father too.
Every year, me, mom, and grandma were the last ones up.
Everyone else would fall asleep and we'd be left with the dishes.
That's how we always saw the old year go out and the new year come in.
Something serious must have happened here.
But no one talks about it.
They never mention their father.
The tour will begin in June.
Here, have some.
Don't you feel hungry?
I didn't want to wake you, but you should eat.
Oh, really?
Have some pickled plums too.
I think it'll still be refreshing for you even though you can't taste very much right now.
Um, wait.
Didn't I say that earlier?
Whenever I was sick, that's what my mom used to say to me.
And here I am, saying the same thing she said.
Whenever she'd bring up the pickled plums, I'd think, there she goes again.
But it was always comforting.
Mom's words always made me feel better, like magic.
But she was gone before Momo had a chance to know that.
Poor thing.
I, um, can't thank you enough for all you've done.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
On such an important day like New Year's Eve, you brought me here and took care of me,
even though I'm not really part of your family.
No, you're wrong.
I wanted you to be here.
You're the one who helped me.
If you weren't here right now,
the truth is I'd probably be cleaning up by myself and crying.
So I can't thank you enough for being here with us.
Hey, wait.
What's wrong, Rei?
Why are you crying?
Oh no, you'll make me cry.
As we sat there together, drying our eyes and sniffling,
we could hear the New Year's Eve bells ringing on TV.
Another sad year coming to an end, vanishing into the night.
I had been so distracted by my own loneliness
that I had failed to see it in the others around me.
It was a sad realization.
The New Year's Eve bells rang in my heart,
filling me with emotion.
Just like a wide river softly flowing,
the New Year had begun,
moving slowly on its way.
What on earth?
Which one of you put stickers on my drawers?
I'm sorry.
Do you know how hard it is to peel this off?
Mom and...
Chihiro.
A dream?
Hey, Rei.
Good morning.
Hi, Rei.
How do you feel?
Akari says it's time for us to have breakfast.
I'll be right there.
How's your fever?
I think it's gone down.
I should be fine now.
Hey, good morning, everyone.
Good morning.
Happy New Year, Rei.
Hey, Happy New Year.
There are so many ads in the paper today.
Packed!
What are you doing, Momo?
I'm reading the paper.
Would you like some mochi, Rei?
What's happening?
I'll have sweet soy sauce.
Cheese for Momo.
Uh, then I'll have cheese, too.
Then let's move on.
Please, go ahead.
Hello there.
Happy New Year.
How are you all doing this morning?
You still have a fever.
Well, let's get some food in you.
Then take your medicine.
Get under the kotatsu.
You can warm your feet under here.
I think the mailman's here.
I've got the New Year's pose eyes!
This one's for me.
That's for Akari.
One for me.
Another one.
Akari.
And that's for Ampah's.
Here's one for you, Momo.
For me?
What?
What is it?
Yeah, what's that?
So?
Are there a lot?
Yeah.
I think we got more than last year.
Wow.
And Momo, too?
How exciting.
Uh-huh.
Oh, yeah.
You might have some, right?
At your place.
Oh, huh.
At my place?
I don't think so.
Oh, go get him!
You stay right here.
I won't be lost.
I just need to borrow your shoes.
Hold on.
Then you'll find out how pathetic I really am.
Hi.
I'm back.
So, um, you did get a few.
Looks like two.
Yeah, just two.
What?
I got some?
I didn't think I'd get any.
Who's this from?
Ah!
It's Badoo!
He calls that a cottage?
Looks like a palace!
Wait, he's also got a hot air balloon?
No, that can't really be his.
So who's this one from?
Ta-da!
Tata-nori Jinguji, 16th Grandmaster Chairman of the Japan Shogi Association.
Chairman?
Um, what about Shogi?
And with the sailfish?
Who is that?
Relation?
I can't believe he went ahead with him.
I'll say this.
He was a strong player.
Although he's always been a bit off.
But even with this, keep in mind that he served as a Grandmaster for seven terms.
Wait, why am I defending him?
Hey, everybody!
Happy New Year!
Your Aunt Misaki's here!
Done!
Ah, it feels good to finally be home.
Going to my husband's parents' house always makes my shoulders sore.
Aunt Misaki!
Now I can finally relax.
That's because you're not yourself there.
You've always cared a little too much about keeping up appearances.
And you're pretty good at it, too.
Oh!
New Year's money!
Hina, Momo, here you go!
Thank you, Aunt Misaki!
I can't wait to spend it!
I like it!
And for you, Dad!
Oh, for me, too!
Are you sure?
This is for Akari!
Really, Misaki?
Thanks a lot!
And here!
For our very special guest, the Shogi Boy!
Don't get too excited!
Your Akari kidnapped you after you got a cold on New Year's Eve!
Wait, what?
But why?
I can't take that from you!
Of course you can!
Not long ago, you brought Issa and Mr. Smith to my club, after all!
I'll be counting on you to do it again!
And finally...
This is for you, Mom.
Mikako, I came over for a visit.
Happy New Year!
Please bring us some more good luck.
Hey, Misaki.
Are you gonna make Akari work again this year?
Stop using your relatives and just hire a new girl already.
I never agreed to this, you know.
I don't want Akari in dangerous situations.
Just calm down.
You know my club's not a dangerous place.
It may be small, but it's refined.
We mainly cater to regulars anyway.
You know I treasure that club.
Yeah, that's what you always say.
Do you intend to keep Akari here doing all the housework and raising the kids until she's an old woman?
She's an earnest girl.
So she's committed to being a mother figure if she has to be.
But she also needs to be pushed to put on makeup, wear a pretty outfit, and go out twice a week.
She is a woman, after all.
Even though she's a true beauty, what about her future?
She may never marry if she's worn out by housework.
Don't worry. I won't allow anyone to lay a finger on Akari at my club.
No. Instead, I'll take their money without them ever touching her.
You see, it's very delicate.
If the clients can't touch her, they'll get all worked up.
And then they'll start throwing money at the unattainable.
While I make my move and grab it.
Ah! Honey! Your daughter is a true demon!
You gave birth to a hot-blooded demon!
Ah!
Are you going to be staying for dinner?
Hina and I have been working hard to make everything just right.
Sure. You don't have to twist my arm.
Your uncle went to a soccer game anyway.
Wow! Amazing!
Ta-da!
It took a lot of hard work to make all of that.
And it all looks so modern. How nice!
Hina and I came up with it.
We put a lot of creative thought into each piece.
But our goal was to make delicious, traditional New Year's food.
It felt kind of boring to just cut fish cake into slices.
So instead, we pounded the fish paste into balls and put them on skewers to look like cute little dumplings.
You can't live a hearty life without pork and beans.
For wealth, we made golden mashed sweet potatoes and chestnuts.
Look through the holes in the lotus root and you can see a bright future ahead.
Staying firmly rooted with the help of burdock root meat rolls.
We pray that Grandpa lives long like turtles do, so mini hamburger turtles.
And there's rolled omelet mixed with fish paste and sweet egg strips.
Oops! I cut little hot dogs into the shape of cute tiny fish.
See?
Both of you are so incredible!
Mikado and Grandmother used to make all the traditional New Year's dishes.
I want biscotti and mine too!
And gum, I want gum too!
That's amazing New Year's food.
Each dish is a different wish.
When I look at this nest of empty boxes, it kind of makes me feel like I have to fill every one of them.
And once we did, the final result was beyond rewarding!
We knew the mission was accomplished!
Cutest food ever!
Yeah!
Exactly!
It's important to cultivate that kind of energy from a sense of achievement in your everyday life.
I know it's true, but it's just so hard to do.
Yeah, a sense of achievement and pain in the neck go hand in hand, but what can you do?
I guess the best way to get that satisfaction is by overcoming the pain in the neck part.
See you later! Thanks for dinner!
I'll see you again soon! Here's to a great New Year!
Oh no! I can't believe it's already this late!
Hina, would you get Momo in the bath?
Sure!
Thanks, I'll handle the dishes.
Rei, there's something I need to ask you.
If you don't mind, we need to use this space.
You're using this space?
Yes. You've never seen it before, but...
The Kawamoto House bath is...
Right here.
What the heck?
Cheek!
Long ago, we didn't have a bath, so we used a public one.
But the family got bigger, so over the years, they decided to add on a bathroom.
I know we're all girls here, but to be completely honest, it'd be really nice if we also had a changing room.
If we did, though, it would take up the rest of the yard and cost a lot of money.
But now, it's kind of embarrassing when we have guests.
Thanks. Sorry about this, Rei.
You're not supposed to look, Rei!
Don't worry. Sorry for being in the way.
Um, well, have a good night!
Yeah, you too!
That was... a total surprise!
I've never seen that before!
What an unusual house!
Well...
I took my medicine.
This string is pretty convenient.
It's kind of strange.
Why am I spending nights here like it's a natural thing to do?
I haven't even known this family for very long.
Why do I feel so at peace when I'm here?
Why does it feel... so right?
I had... dreams of my childhood again.
Why?
Why do I feel so at peace when I'm here?
Why do I feel so at peace?
Oh...
Why do I feel so at peace when I'm here?
I see.
That's what it is.
I had a feeling...
I could tell...
That this old house...
Had time...
And everything...
And everyone...
Even me...
in a gentle embrace,
and then it slowly faded away.
With that in mind,
I finally fell asleep.
It was the kind of deep, peaceful sleep
that I hadn't had in I don't know how many years.
Let's go get it, Kiriyama.
I know this feeling.
This is going to help us save so much money.
Listen, Momo, you see?
I have a match that I just can't lose.
Rei, good luck.
Oh, I'm so busy.
I wish I had another pair of hands.
Then I'll do it.
Please watch the next episode of March Comes In Like a Lion.
Thank you.